instituteforgovernment.org.uk 2018-12-26

# Our privacy policy | The Institute for Government

At the Institute for Government, we are committed to protecting and respecting your privacy.

This policy explains when and why we collect personal information about people who visit our website, how we use it, the conditions under which we may disclose it to others and how we keep it secure.

We may change this policy from time to time so please check this page occasionally to ensure that you’re happy with any changes. By using our website, you’re agreeing to be bound by this policy.

Any questions regarding this policy and our privacy practices should be sent by email to [data@instituteforgovernment.org.uk](mailto:data@instituteforgovernment.org.uk) or by writing to Data Protection, Institute for Government, 2 Carlton Gardens, London SW1Y 5AA. Alternatively, you can telephone 020 7747 0406.

###  **Who are we?**

The Institute for Government is a charity established in 2008 with the mission of improving the effectiveness of government by providing evidence-based advice that draws on best practice from around the world. Institute for Government is a registered charity (no. 1123926) and company limited by guarantee (no. 6480524). The registered address is 2 Carlton Gardens, London SW1Y 5AA. The Institute for Government “group” includes its trading subsidiary IFG Enterprises Limited.

###  **How do we collect information from you?**

We obtain information about you when you use our website, for example, when you contact us about publications and events, or if you register to receive one of our weekly newsletters.

###  **What type of information is collected from you?**

The personal information we collect might include your name, address, email address, IP (internet protocol) address, and information regarding what pages are accessed and when.

###  **How is your information used?**

We may use your information to:

  * process events booking requests that you have submitted
  * to carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into by you and us
  * seek your views or comments on the publications, blogs, events and other information we provide
  * notify you of changes to our services
  * send you communications which you have requested and that may be of interest to you. These may include weekly newsletters, information about forthcoming events, blogs, publications and other information related to our work
  * process a grant or job application.

We review our retention periods for personal information on a regular basis. We are legally required to hold some types of information to fulfil our statutory obligations. We will hold your personal information on our systems for as long as is necessary for the relevant activity, or as long as is set out in any relevant contract you hold with us.

###  **Who has access to your information?**

We will not sell or rent your information to third parties.

We will not automatically share your information with third parties for marketing purposes. If we would like to share your information with third parties in relation to your attendance at a particular event you will be explicitly informed when booking the event and your details would only be provided on an explicit opt-in basis.

####  **Third-party service providers working on our behalf**

We may pass your information to our third-party service providers, agents, subcontractors and other associated organisations for the purposes of completing tasks and providing services to you on our behalf. For example, Infusionsoft provides us with a CRM system (marketing database) and are therefore a data processor with respect to personal data held on this database.

However, when we use third-party service providers, we disclose only the personal information that is necessary to deliver the service and we have a contract in place that requires them to keep your information secure, to confirm that they are compliant with the General Data Protection Regulation and not to use it for their own direct marketing purposes.

Please be reassured that we will not release your information to third parties beyond the Institute for Government for them to use for their own direct marketing purposes, unless you have requested us to do so, or we are required to do so by law, for example, by a court order or for the purposes of prevention of fraud or other crime.

###  **Your choices**

You have a choice about whether or not you wish to receive information from us. If you do not want to receive direct marketing communications from us about our work and our events programme then you can select your choices by ticking the relevant boxes situated on the form on which we collect your information or by opting out by using the link within any communications we send you.

If you are connected to us with a non-business email address we will not contact you for marketing purposes by email, phone or text message unless you have given your prior consent. If you have a business email address the Institute will continue to send you details of our events, publications and news on the basis of having a legitimate interest in highlighting our work. You may at any point opt out of receiving these emails. You can also change your marketing preferences at any time by contacting us by email: [data@instituteforgovernment.org.uk](mailto:data@instituteforgovernment.org.uk) or telephone on 020 7747 0406.

###  **How you can access and update your information**

The accuracy of your information is important to us. We’re working on ways to make it easier for you to review and correct the information that we hold about you. In the meantime, if you change email address, or any of the other information we hold is inaccurate or out of date, please email us at: [data@instituteforgovernment.org.uk](mailto:data@instituteforgovernment.org.uk), or write to us at: Data Protection, Institute for Government, 2 Carlton Gardens, London SW1Y 5AA. Alternatively, you can telephone 020 7747 0406.

You have the right to ask for a copy of the information Institute for Government hold about you to cover our costs in providing you with details of the information we hold about you. We may charge £10 for information requests.

###  **Security precautions in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of your information**

Non-sensitive details (your email address etc.) are transmitted normally over the Internet, and this can never be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee the security of any information you transmit to us, and you do so at your own risk. Once we receive your information, we make our best effort to ensure its security on our systems. Where we have given (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of our websites, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share your password with anyone.

###  **Use of 'cookies'**

Like many other websites, the Institute for Government website uses cookies. 'Cookies' are small pieces of information sent by an organisation to your computer and stored on your hard drive to allow that website to recognise you when you visit. They collect statistical data about your browsing actions and patterns and do not identify you as an individual. For example, we use cookies to store your country preference. This helps us to improve our website and deliver a better more personalised service.

It is possible to switch off cookies by setting your browser preferences. For more information on how to switch off cookies on your computer, visit our full cookies policy. Turning cookies of may result in a loss of functionality when using our website.

###  **Links to other websites**

Our website may contain links to other websites run by other organisations. This privacy policy applies only to our website‚ so we encourage you to read the privacy statements on the other websites you visit. We cannot be responsible for the privacy policies and practices of other sites even if you access them using links from our website.

In addition, if you linked to our website from a third-party site, we cannot be responsible for the privacy policies and practices of the owners and operators of that third-party site and recommend that you check the policy of that third party site.

###  **People aged  under 18**

We are concerned to protect the privacy of children and young peope aged under 18. If you are aged under 18‚ please obtain your parent/guardian's permission beforehand whenever you provide us with personal information.

###  **Transferring your information outside of Europe**

As part of the services offered to you through this website, the information which you provide to us may be transferred to countries outside the European Union (“EU”). By way of example, this may happen if any of our servers are from time to time located in a country outside of the EU. These countries may not have similar data protection laws to the UK. By submitting your personal data, you’re agreeing to this transfer, storing or processing. If we transfer your information outside of the EU in this way, we will take steps to ensure that appropriate security measures are taken with the aim of ensuring that your privacy rights continue to be protected as outlined in this policy.

If you use our services while you are outside the EU, your information may be transferred outside the EU in order to provide you with those services.

###  **Review of this policy**

We keep this policy under regular review. This policy was last updated in April 2018.
